Guide to the James Lippincott Goodwin Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- James L. Goodwin "Personal" Correspondence, 1882-1967; Series VII
  - Photographs, 1892-1905 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    Early childhood photographs of James L. Goodwin and his family; Photographs of him on the Groton crew and those of Mr. Goodwin as a young college man.
  - Photographs and Clippings, 1913-1964 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    Newspaper clippings of conservation meetings, marketing problems in New England and personal accounts of Mr. Goodwin's career; Photograph and news article of Trinity College concerning an Honorary Degree in 1963; 1964 clipping and photograph of Mr. Goodwin transferring 1,722 acres of Pine Acres to the Connecticut Conservation and Recreation Program; 1966 Photograph of him accepting the Twenty-fifth Tree Farm Award at Pine Acres Farm and the 1967 Obituaries of his death.
- Great Pond Nursery and Tree Farm Correspondence, 1935-1967; Series VIII
  - Great Pond Accounts, 1953-1964 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Forestry accounts including figures on labor, machinery and timber cut, from 1953-1964; Inventory, 1953-1955; Schedule of Capital and Agriculture.
  - Great Pond Nursery, 1935-1942 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Correspondence with E. W. Britton, State Entomologist regarding leaf scale found in general inspection; Henry W. Hickock, Consulting on disease of Red Pine; Herbst Brothers: Connecticut Agriculture State Booklets; Connecticut Nursery Inspection and Registration Certificates and Special Price List to members of the Connecticut Forest and Park Association of Evergreens for forest plantings.
  - Great Pond Nursery, 1944-1948 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    June Nursery Inventories, 1930-1944; Correspondence with George Cromie regarding his discovery of the ideal Christmas Tree; Herbst Brothers Orders; Connecticut Nursery Inspection and Registration Certificates; Price list of Pine and Spruce Transplants; Stock Inventories and Nursery Sales.
  - Great Pond Nursery, 1946-1951 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Annual Reports and Annual Balance Statements, 1947-1950; Price list to members of Talcott Mountain Forest Protection Association; Herbst Brothers Orders; Stock Inventory and Consultation with members of Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station concerning diagnosis and treatment of any diseases in nursery stock.
  - Great Pond Nursery, Nursery Orders, 1930-1933, 1935-1937, 1942-1943 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Correspondence of 1933 includes Sale of Red Pine Transplants for use in the Works Progress Administration Program; Nursery Sales for these years and inventory of stock.
  - Great Pond Nursery Plantings, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Inventory of stock, 1949-1950; Talcott Mountain Protective Association, 1950; Planting and Nursery Sales listed by customers; State of Connecticut Nursery and Registration Certificate.
  - Great Pond Nursery Price List Requests, 1958-1967 (Box 23, Folder 6a)
    List of names and letters requesting price lists.
  - Great Pond Nursery Sales of Transplants, 1951 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    Correspondence includes a purchase order for 5,000 Norway Spruce by the State Forest and Park Commission; 1950 Price List to members of the Talcott Mountain Forest Protective Association and sales of transplants to these members; Inventory of stock and sales of transplants, 1951.
  - Great Pond Nursery, Sales of Transplants, 1952 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    Summary of stock inventory; Customer billing; Sales of stock; Great Pond Property Sales and Connecticut Nursery Inspection Registration Certificate.
  - Great Pond Nursery, Sale of Transplants, 1953 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    Price list to the Talcott Mountain Forest Association with orders from the members; June Great Pond Nursery stock inventory; Work sheet of the Talcott Mountain Association planting and of Great Pond Property Sales.
  - Great Pond Nursery, Sale of Transplants, 1954 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    June, July inventory of stock; Inventory of capital and loss; Sale of Transplants; Work Sheets; Orders for transplants from members of the Talcott Mountain Protective Association.
  - Great Pond Nursery Transplants, 1954-1955 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    Price lists, orders, confirmation of orders and mailing list for catalogs; Directions to Great Pond Nursery; Inventories of transplants; Statements; Sales paid by cash or check; Sales billed for transplants; Connecticut Nursery Inspection and Registration Certificate.
  - Great Pond Nursery Transplants, 1955-1956 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    Inventory of White Pine, White Spruce, Norway Spruce, and Hemlock for the years, 1955-1956; List of Simsbury Sales; Orders for transplants and acknowledgments from J. L. Goodwin and Harold Sweeton, Superintendent, Great Pond Nursery; Billings and Sales; Harold Sweeton corresponding with James L. Goodwin concerning damage of the White Spruce Transplants by the winter weather.
  - Great Pond Nursery Transplants, 1956 (Box 24, Folder 12a)
    Order Blanks; Work Papers; Spring List for 1956; List of 1956 Transplants to be billed and Nursery Sales; Statements of Paid Sales of Trees and Shrubs and Resale Sales; Correspondence regarding information and prices on evergreen for fall planting; Inventory of White Pine, White Spruce, Norway Spruce and Fruit Bearing Shrubs; List of Number of Trees and Kind; Cost Tax and adjustments; List of Trees from Seed-Beds.
  - Great Pond Nursery Transplants, 1956-1957 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    Orders for securing Norway Spruce, 4 year, and Balsam Seedlings; Order Blanks; Transplant Orders for 1957; Spring List for 1957; Correspondence mainly with Harold Sweeton, Superintendent, Great Pond Nursery and various customers relating to cancelling of orders, requesting orders of various transplants; Inquiries of Nursery Stock; Sales of Transplants - April-June 30, 1957; Inventories of Transplants, 1956 and 1957; Marketing Cost, September 30, 1957.
  - Great Pond Nursery Transplants, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    Inventory of Transplants, September 30, 1957; Statement of Sales of Transplants; Spring price list for 1958; Nursery Sales for 1958; Orders for transplants; Inquiries from customers to Harold Sweeton about planting stock; Price list for hardwood stock.
  - Great Pond Nursery Transplants, 1959 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    Inventory of Transplants, September 30, 1958 and 1959; Transplant Orders, October 1, 1958, September 30, 1959; Sales of Transplants, January 1, 1959 - March 31, 1959; Correspondence between Harold Sweeton, James L. Goodwin and customers concerning planting nursery stock; Orders for various transplants; Price list; Cancellations of orders for transplants; Letter of acknowledgment from Sydney Howe, Executive Director, The Farmington River Watershed Association to James L. Goodwin for his donation of 2,000 White Spruce Seedling; Harold H. Sweeton acknowledging his appreciation to Harold Aseltine, The New England Homestead, for the advertisement of Christmas Tree Planting stock; Spruce Price List; various receipts from customers; Work sheets pertaining to Trees Shipped; Inventory of Proportion Overhead on Transplants Distributed; Marketing Cost; Simsbury Transplants.
  - Great Pond Nursery Transplants, 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    Correspondence between Harold H. Sweeton, and Arthur C. Bobb, Extension Pomologist, University of Connecticut concerning planting Fraser Fir and the policy of sales; Inventory of Transplanting for September 30, 1959; Price list for 1960 and confirmation of orders from Harold Sweeton; Statement of transplants October 1, 1959 - September 30, 1960; 1960 Transplants Sale; Sales of Transplants, January - March 31, 1960 - June 30, 1960; Spring Price List, 1960; Cash Receipts; Advertisement in the New England Homestead about Christmas Tree Planting Stock; Quality Transplants; J. L. Goodwin requesting various orders of seed from Herbst Brothers Seedsman, Incorporated, and Forestry Associates.
  - Great Pond Nursery Transplants, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 16a)
    Orders for Nursery stock; Work sheet of checks for April 29, 1960; Sales relating to Simsbury, May 6, 1960; Nursery Sales; Cash Sales; Sales of Transplants, July 1, 1960 - September 30, 1960; Inventory, September 30, 1960; Statements relating to proportion overhead on transplants distributed; Marketing Cost; Simsbury Transplants.
  - Great Pond Nursery Transplants, 1960-1961 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    Inventory of Great Pond Nursery September 30, 1960; Sales of Transplants reported by Harold H. Sweeton; Orders for transplants, seeds, seedlings, and price list of various nursery stock; Cash receipts of transplants, January 1, 1961 - June 30, 1961; Sales of Transplants January 1, 1961 - June 30, 1961; Correspondence regarding inquiries of nursery planting stock; Price list of White Pine, Norway Spruce, White Spruce, Balsam Fir and Scotch Pine; Nursery Bills for 1961; Correspondence between Harold Sweeton, Arthur E. McEvoy, The New Britain Memorial Hospital, Director of Public Relations and James L. Goodwin regarding the purchase of evergreen seedlings for planting; Sales of Transplants June 30, 1961; Inventory of Nursery, September 30, 1961; Proportion Overhead on Transplants Distributed; Marketing Cost; Simsbury Transplants 1961, Transplant Orders.
  - Great Pond Nursery Transplants, 1961-1962 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    Nursery Sales, 1962; Sales of Transplants, January 1, 1930 - June 30, 1962; Tree Order-Spring, 1962; Various orders of transplants, seedlings, and seeds; Request for price list of various nursery stock; Bills to customers from Nursery and Tree Farm; Cancellation of orders; Price list of 1962; Inventory of Nursery, 1962; Connecticut Nursery Inspection Certificate.
  - Great Pond Nursery, 1962-1963 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    Inventory of Great Pond Nursery, September 30, 1962; Sales of Transplants January 1, 1963 - June 30, 1963; Inquiries relating to purchases of Balsam Fir Transplants and other nursery stock; Sales of Transplants - January 1, 1930 June 30, 1963; Spring Price List; Statements, Simsbury Transplants and Transplant Orders, 1963; Bills rendered to customers; Confirmation and acknowledgments of orders.
  - Great Pond Nursery Transplants, 1963-1964 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    Inventory of Nursery, September 30, 1963; Transplant Orders, October 1, 1963 - September 30, 1964; Sale of Transplants, January 1, 1964 - June 30, 1964; Mailing list - Great Pond Nursery; Statement pertaining to purchase order; Correspondence relating to orders for transplants, seedlings, and trees; Various work sheets; Bills and receipts to customers; Shipment of Nursery Stock; Inventory of Nursery September 30, 1964; List of Simsbury Transplants; Sales of Transplants, October 1, 1964 - December 31, 1964.
  - Great Pond Nursery Transplants, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    Orders for stock, January 1, 1965 - June 30, 1965; Inventory of Paid Sales of Transplants; October 1, 1964 - September 30, 1965 Transplant Orders and Stock Inventory.
  - Great Pond Nursery Transplants, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    Sales of Transplants; Price list Brochures; Customer order forms and State of Connecticut Sales and Use Tax Division Certificates.
  - Great Pond Nursery and Tree Farm, Cordwood and Logs, 1942-1952 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    Correspondence between James L. Goodwin and Nursery Manager, Harold Sweeton regarding the decision to divide Great Pond in-to the following tracts: Tomalonis, Holcomb, Pasture, Eddy, Nursery, Pond North Tract; Growth study of the Tomalonis Tract, 1948; Wood Sales, 1948; 1947-1948 Great Pond Forestry Accounts - Expenses and Receipts; Cordwood Sales, 1950-1951; Wood Inventory, 1956.
  - Great Pond Nursery and Tree Farm - Cordwood and Logs, 1924-1963 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    Great Pond Annual Statements, 1940-1943; Growth Study of the Tomalonis Tract, 1953; List of Cordwood Sales, October to December 1958, 1959, 1960, 1961, 1962.
  - Great Pond Nursery and Tree Farm, Cordwood and Logs, 1963-1966 (Box 26, Folder 24a)
    Sales of Cordwood, October to December 1963-1966.
  - Great Pond Nursery and Tree Farm, Cordwood and Logs, 1951-1955 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    Cordwood Sales and Lumber Sales June 1952 - May 1953; June 1953 May 1955; Inventories of Great Pond and correspondence between Harold Sweeton and J. L. Goodwin reporting the spraying of stock against Gypsy Moth by helicopter.
  - Great Pond Nursery and Tree Farm, Cordwood and Logs, 1965-1967 (Box 27, Folder 25a)
    Cordwood and Lumber Sales, June 1955 to May 1966, October to December, 1957; Purchase order from Cordwood, Incorporated.
  - Great Pond Nursery and Tree Farm, Cordwood and Logs, 1965-1967 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    Wood Inventory, Fall 1965; Sales of Cordwood, October to December, 1966, and January to March, 1967.
  - Great Pond Nursery and Tree Farm, General, 1949-1956 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    Nursery Inspection and Registration Certificates; Planting and Inventories; Procedures for job and work classification for the Forestry and Nursery Over-head, Lake Improvement, Land Improvement, Roads, and Trails Maintenance, and Wild Life Care; Herbst Brothers Seedmen's Incorporated Seed Orders; Tomalonis Tract History; Acceptance of the Tree Farm Award for Great Pond Nursery, 1956 and Preparation of Maps of Great Pond for Tourists.
  - Great Pond Nursery and Tree Farm, General, 1957-1960 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    Purchase Orders for Fire Fighting Equipment; Seed Orders from Herbst Brothers for Pine and Fir Seed; Connecticut Nursery Inspection and Registration Certificates; Consultation with the Connecticut Agriculture Experiment Station concerning Inspection of stock.
  - Great Pond Nursery, and Tree Farm, General, 1961-1963 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    Correspondence between James L. Goodwin and Harold Sweeton includes Use of Great Pond by such groups as. a Conservation Work Shop arranged by Professor of Forestry, Raymond Kienholz, and Hartford National Bank, Trustees; Correspondence also includes Herbst Brothers Seed Orders, Purchase of the G. L. Engel Land adjoining Great Pond, and Statements of Expenses and Receipts.
  - Great Pond Nursery and Tree Farm, General, 1964-1967 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    Herbst Brothers Seed Orders; Invoice for the delivery of Fire Fighting Pumps; Purchase of Whitman Property adjoining Great Pond and celebration of the Silver Anniversary of the American Tree Farm System at Great Pond Forest, 1966.
  - Great Pond Nursery and Tree Farm, Summary, 1947-1958 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    Quarterly Sales of Use Tax Return, 1947-1958; Unincorporated Business Tax Returns, 1958-1959.
  - Great Pond Nursery and Tree Farm, 1949-1966 (Box 28, Folder 31a)
    This correspondence includes State of Connecticut Resale Certificates, 1949, 1954; Tax Returns, 1959-1966; Great Pond Sale of Transplants, 1960-1966.
  - Great Pond Property, 1941-1942 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    Pay-roll expenses of Simsbury, 1941-1942.
  - Great Pond Property, 1943-1947 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    Inventories, 1930-1943; Individual Rhododendrom Orders, 1940-1945; List of Annual Plantings, 1930-1934; 1943 Claim Report; 1943 Accident Report.
  - Great Pond Property, 1947-1949 (Box 28, Folder 33a)
    1947 Great Pond Capital Account including statistics of Lake Improvement, Land Improvement, Wild Life, and Plantations; Acknowledgment of thanks from Orrin Kilbourn for use of the Goodwin "Commandos" for apple-picking, 1948; Connecticut Agricultural Station diagnosis of bark beetle.
  - Great Pond, Harold Sweeton, 1941-1965 (Box 28, Folder 33b)
    1941 Correspondence between Mr. Sweeton and the United States Department of Agriculture concerning Conservation Planning. It also includes an Essay of Great Pond Forest by James L. Goodwin; List of Wild Flowers and Birds at Great Pond Forest.
  - Great Pond Wild Life, 1936-1941 (Box 28, Folder 34)
    1936 Certificate of Merit Award to James L. Goodwin from John C. Huntington, Vice President, More Game Birds in America, Incorporated; Correspondence with Mildred Bartle, Executive Secretary, State Board of Fisheries regarding a report of the Water Fowl Refuge established by James L. Goodwin, 1935; 1937 Correspondence with Governor Wilbur L. Cross approving the policies of Arthur L. Clark, Superintendent, State Board of Fisheries and Game, and correspondence with R. W. Williams, United States Department, Interior, Bureau of Biological Survey giving permission to Mr. Goodwin to Wing Clip Canada Geese, 1939-1940.
  - Great Pond Wild Life, 1941-1956 (Box 28, Folder 35)
    Brochures and price list from Sunny Field Farm for game; Terrell's Aquatic and Smith's Patented Turtle Traps giving list of domestic buyers of turtle meat; Connecticut State Board of Fisheries and Game Breeders Licenses from 1938-1944; 1944 Connecticut State Board of Fisheries and Game Report; National Wildlife Federation Certificate to J. L. Goodwin, 1956; "In the Cause of Conservation".
  - Nursery and Forest Accounts, 1931-1963 (Box 29)
    Great Pond Tree Farm Accounts, 1941-1960; Great Pond Forest Accounts, 1941-1961; Great Pond Nursery Inventory, 1954, 1956, and 1961; Great Pond Nursery Accounts, 1960-1963; Summary of work operations on the following tracts: Holcomb, Tomalonis, Pasture, Pond North, Sheppard, and Tract North cover the years 1941-1960; Work Sheets on Seed Beds, 1931-1947; Nursery Capital Account, 1935-1948.
  - Great Pond Nursery Order and Payroll Books, 1954-1965 (Box 30)
- Pine Acres Farm Correspondence, 1918-1965; Series IX
  - A, General, 1920-1955 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    Correspondence between Mr. Goodwin and various people concerned with Pine Acres Farm such as employees, rentees; directive on apple growing and ordering agricultural equipment.
  - Annual Report Records, 1940-1941 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    Inventories of lumber on hand, returned, delivered, dressed and planed, stacked, sawed, cut, skidded, hauled, scaled and of the Garden and Grounds.
  - C. W. Atwater and Son, 1919-1925 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    Atwater Nurserymen offer fruit trees for sale and advice on maintenance to Mr. Goodwin.
  - B, General, 1925-1962 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    Capitalized expense sheet of the Van Durr House, Chapel House Garage, Barn Tenement; a report of Solon Barraclugh, "Working Plan for a Series of Case Studies in the Economics of Forest Management"; contribution to the Episcopal Brewster Foundation at Yale; Correspondence with L. W. Button, agent, for Aetna Insurance Company regarding insurance on the farm property and effects.
  - Burpee, W. Atlee Company, Philadelphia, 1922-1950 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    Mr. Goodwin's seed orders for flower and vegetable.
  - C, General, 1938-1965 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    Correspondence with Caterpillar Tractor Company allowing the use of the enclosed photograph of Mr. Goodwin's Diesel Tractor for advertisements; 1959 Census Summary; Connecticut Christmas Tree Growers Association; Preliminary Report on the deed to the Curtiss Tavern in Hampton.
  - Cannon House, 1919-1949 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    Correspondence with the tenants living in the various farm houses, Ford, Cannon, Van Durr; Tabulations of expenses and receipts of renting houses, generally to Goodwin farm employees; Correspondence with Edson C. Stocking, Manager of the Farm, eventual purchaser of the Cannon House.
  - Chapel House, Hampton, 1933-1949 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    Correspondence with Richard Button regarding the Aetna Insurance on the house; dispute about the employee Stanley Galentski; Easement Rights to the Connecticut Light and Power Company.
  - Cedar Swamp Road, Pine Acres Lake, 1918-1962 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    1937 Correspondence with Shepard B. Palmer, Member of the State Board of Civil Engineers complaining that the Cedar Swamp Dam was of faulty construction and perilous to the adjacent highway. Continuing controversial correspondence about the town of Hampton's decision to close Cedar Swamp Road with research by Attorneys, W. Arthur Countryman, Jr. and Harry Back, Jr., delving back to 1918 Town History; Senate Bill 336 Connecticut concerning "Angling in Private Waters", and the abstract of a survey and map of the Pearl Esterbrook parcels.
  - The Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station, 1939-1959 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    Notice of Field Days and diagnoses of plant disease.
  - Connecticut Bank and Trust Company, Windham Office, 1960-1964 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    Routine correspondence with the bank including deposit receipts.
  - Connecticut Forestry Department, C. C. C. Camps, 1940 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    List of Civilian Conservation Camps in Connecticut and a tabulation of time and type of work done for Mr. Goodwin in 1938 and 1939.
  - Connecticut State College, Storrs, 1921-1922, 1927, 1939, 1934, 1937 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    Exchange of Agricultural Information between researchers at the Connecticut Agricultural College and Mr. Stocking and Mr. Goodwin.
  - Connwood, Incorporated, 1948-1961 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    Bills, receipts, tabulations and commissions on sales transacted between Pine Acres and Connwood.
  - D, General, 1939-1960 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    Correspondence with Attorney Roger W. Davis regarding the settlement of claims by Mr. Goodwin against various delinquent tenants and customers; customer's purchases of stock from Pine Acres Farm and chemicals purchased by Mr. Goodwin from Du Pont Company.
  - Dams, New: Black Spruce Pond, Spring Pond, Brown Hill Pond, 1956-1959 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    1956 Legislative "Private Waters", Connecticut State Board for Supervision of Dams Permit for construction of these three dams; Connecticut State Board of Fisheries and Game Registration of Private Waters; Wildlife Management Agreement entered into by Mr. Goodwin and the State of Connecticut.
  - Diana's Pool, 1943-1952 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    Correspondence between Mr. Goodwin and interested conservationists, who by utilizing the provisions of George Dudley Seymour Residue Trust, aid the State of Connecticut in securing Diana's Pool, a recreational area in the Natchaug River in Chaplin. There is also the Last Will and Testament of George Dudley Seymour.
  - Edward F. Dibble, Seed Growers, 1920-1923 (Box 32, Folder 18)
    Four seed orders for vegetable and flower seed.
  - E, General, 1942-1963 (Box 32, Folder 19)
    Correspondence with an employee on the farm, Lloyd Edwards and wife, a housekeeper there.
  - Estabrooks, Joseph, 1943-1944 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    Correspondence and directives from Mr. Goodwin and his secretary Edna Millard to Joseph Estabrooks, foreman of Pine Acres, during Mr. Stocking illness.
  - F, General, 1921-1955 (Box 32, Folder 21)
    Correspondence with farm produce; exchange of information with the Forest Service, United States Department of Agriculture; Directives to farm workers.
  - Farmhouse Addition, 1947-1949 (Box 32, Folder 22)
    This folder contains correspondence with Mr. Goodwin's brother Philip Goodwin, Architect, and paint and electrical contractors.
  - Farmhouse Bathroom, 1951-1954 (Box 32, Folder 23)
    This folder contains the plumbing order from the Willimantic Plumbing Company and correspondence about general farm repairs.
  - Farm File, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 24)
    This correspondence with Franklin Forestry Company, Boston, concerns Mr. Goodwin's dissatisfaction with nursery stock ordered from this company.
  - Forest Management, 1923, 1927, 1932, 1937 (Box 32, Folder 25)
    This folder contains correspondence with State Forester, A. F. Hawes and Professors Chapman and Hawley regarding the value of pine plantation, setting up a cost account system for the Hampton Forest and various tabulations such as "Area Burned over at Pine Acres, 1927; Spruce Plantation, 1914-1925 Receipts and Expenses."
  - Forestry Records, 1928-1940 (Box 32, Folder 26)
    This folder contains the acreage figures for Hampton, Chaplin and Orchard Hill Forests.
  - G, General, 1943-1960 (Box 32, Folder 27)